IGBINOSA IWINOSA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Telephone: +2349061444849 E-mail: <u>Igbinosaiwinosao1@gmail.com</u>

 $Linked In \ Address: \underline{www.linkedin.com/in/igbinosaiwinosa} \\ Portfolio \ Link: \underline{https://www.iwinosa.me} \\$

I am a process-focused, performance driven and skilled Front-End Developer with over 4 years of working experience. I take pride in my work and make certain that I build state-of-the-art, easy to use and user-friendly websites and applications. I'm capable of scaling up an organization by building high quality working websites, which all contributes to the overall success of the company's product suite.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Spendwiseng Fintech

Senior Front End Web Developer

March 2022 - Till Date

- Built a financial service that allows users manage their expenses, receive, hold, and make payments in multiple currencies, create virtual and physical cards, and pay bills seamlessly.
- Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers.
- Collaborate with leadership, product managers, business analysts and mobile developers to identify problems and creatively solve complex problems

Ridiculously Chasing Brand

Front End Web Developer

Nov 2021 - Feb 2022

- Spearheaded a team in building the company's website.
- Worked in a team alongside web developers, and UI/UX designers, to ensure all elements of web creation were consistent.
- Developed features that enhanced the users experience.

De-hive Computer Institute

Front End Web Developer

Jan 2019- Oct 2021

- Ensured quick updates on products to make them effective.
- Built websites for the company's clients.
- Optimized web pages for maximum speed and scalability.

Freelancer

Front End Web Developer

Apr 2018 – Jan 2019

PROJECTS

• Ounje Bazaar - Project & Frontend Lead.

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

- Ounje Bazaar is an integrated digital marketplace for international, cultural and ethnic groceries in New Brunswick, Canada.
- The website also features a database of recipes to offer users ideas about how to prepare their newly purchased ethnic groceries.
- This project won the MTME Next award in Canada.

- I was responsible for managing the project and heading the Engineering team.
- Here is the Live link https://ounjebazaar.netlify.app/
- Designed and built a fully functional Bookshop website.

Nov 2021

- Technologies used:- React, SCSS, Figma, Netlify, Github & Commerce JS
- Integrated Stripe as a payment gateway and used chec.io API to send invoices to users mail.
- Used Commerce Js to fetch and store the products, also to handle the cart functions.
- Used netlify to deploy the website.
- Here is the Live link https://bookhomes.netlify.app/

VOLUNTEER AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Women Build, University of Lagos Founder and Tutor
- ECX, University of Lagos Front-end Mentor and Tutor.
- Ingressive 4 Good, University of Lagos Lead Tutor
- Google Developer Student Club, University of Lagos Front-end Tutor.
- Empower Programme University of Lagos Lead Tutor
- Google Developers Group Lagos, DevFest Lagos Volunteer.

Dec 2021

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION:

AltSchool Africa. Expected Dec 2022

Program: Diploma in Software Engineering

University of Lagos, Akoka, Lagos.

Expected Oct 2022

Program: Bachelor of Science and Education in progress in Home Economics Science

and Education.

ST. Michael Secondary School, Ibafo, Ogun State

Sept 2014 - May 2017

WASSCE (West African Senior School Leaving Certificate)

SKILLS AND INTERESTS:

- **Technical Skills and Tools:** React, REST API, Context API, AWS S3, Google APIs (Maps, Calendar), SCSS, GSAP, Sentry, Tailwind, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, Netlify, Git.
- **Soft skills:** Strong communication skills, great teamwork ability, good leadership skills, problem-solving skills.